你的血已经表态了
Your blood has spoken.
你已经选好边了
You have chosen a side.
哪边？
What side?
你是黑暗派
You are dark.
滚粗
Bull-shit.
我怎么可能是黑暗派
There's no freaking way I'm Dark Fae.
Bo 淫妖 不结盟 这是我的标志
Bo. Succubus. Unaligned.It's kinda my brand.
我们的石像鬼读过你的血了
Our gargoyle read your blood.
你现在是黑暗派
You have joined the Dark.
好笑 要是我背叛了我的信仰
Funny, you'd think I'd remember betraying
我起码会记得
everything I've ever stood for.
告诉你个秘密 小盆友
A mystery for you, Youngling ...
那个你消失期间领导黑暗派的他
and he who led the Dark during your absence.
Vex?
我们 不管咋说 很满意
We, however, are satisfied.
你可以走了
You may take your leave.
我可以走了？
Oh, may I?
大姐 这是我的地盘
Buddy, this is my town.
要说该走
If anyone's taking a leave,
那也是你和你的何弃疗党羽
it's you and your circle-jerk of doom...
你要是见到人类医生或者你那人类恐怖分子宠物
And if you see the human Doctor or that terrorist pet of yours
跟她们说我们会很快召见她们的
tell them we will see them soon.
你说啥？
What did you say?
她们是异种的敌人
They are enemies of the Fae.
她们会死得很惨
Their deaths will be most painful.
特么够了
And there it is.
你特么到底是什么牌子的碧池
What kind of boomerang bitch are you?
攻击Una Mens只会反噬你自身
Strike at the Una Mens and you shall be your own victim.
现在 结盟的淫妖 给你选择
For now, aligned Succubus, a choice:
要么立刻向黑暗首领表示你的忠诚 要么死
Pay fealty to the leader of the Dark at once ... or die.
你充好电了？
Are you adequately juiced?
那些Una Mens到处乱搞
Those Una Mens assholes pack quite a wallop.
狼叔又不在城里 我总得想点办法
And with Dyson out of town, I gotta find some way
给自己的DD充满电
to recharge the double Ds.
能量 我的能量啊
The batteries. My batteries.
我就想找到流浪者然后把一切都扯清
Anyway, I just want to find the Wanderer and get this cleared up.
你觉得流浪者就是那个在背后捣鬼
You think the Wanderer is behind the ol' "whoops
把你不小心弄成了黑暗派的人
I tripped and accidentally joined club evil?"
绝对是他
Has to be.
他绑架了我诶
He takes me against my will,
还把我弄失忆
wipes my memory,
我一回家就变黑暗派了
and when I get home I'm Dark Fae?
我还要跟你说谁也在掺和
And I'll tell you who else is tied up in this...
莫非是亲爱的Vex?
Vex-meister General?
*Clunge-meister general 男性万人迷*
Una Mens说他和这事牵扯很多
Una Mens says he's deep in da bullcacky.
他是黑暗恶棍的新头头
He's the new leader of Los Dark Douchebags.
可我们是多好的化妆基友啊
But we were such good mascara buddies.
不过他确实派Clio去剥你头皮了
Although he did send Clio to kinda scalp you.
恩 老娘要踩他踩到他告诉我
Well, I'm gonna put the boots to Vex until he tells me where
流浪者在哪还有我怎么干掉他为止
the Wanderer is and how I kill him.
等等，狼叔还在……？
Wait up, Dyson is still...?
找Lauren 嗯
Looking for Lauren. Yeah.
你的爱情生活真是各种单调啊
Glad to see your love life finally got less complicated.
他必须找到她
He has to find her.
他会的
He will.
她一定要没事
And she has to be okay.
她会的
She will.
爱你 傲骄小盆友
I love you, Sassafraz.
我知道
I know.
现在到69号了
Now serving 69!
看吧
No duh.
喂等下
Oh, look.
你要是黑暗了 是不是说我也变黑暗了
If you're Dark,  does that mean I'm Dark too?
因为我得 提升下形象
Cuz I'm gonna need like,a serious image upgrade.
我们要谈谈置装费
We should talk clothing allowance...
相信我 我们不会黑暗很久的
Trust me.We won't be Dark for long.
啊 现在到69号
Ahem. Now serving 69.
好吧
Right.
现在到69号
Now serving 69.
我是黑暗派了？
I'm dark?
Bo！
Bo!
我好高兴你终于加入我们了
I am so glad you could finally join us.
本作品片源来自互联网，仅供个人影视制作学习交流之用
任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途
挪威金毛的胡须最有爱了字幕组  r(st)q
英文字幕：来自互联网
翻译：Neffititi  骷髅头正宫_K   精校：Momou各N大  李夹碎  Joy   压制：Joy
发布：百度贴吧Tamsin后援群
资源下载请关注瓦尔基里字幕组官方微博
4x05 - Let the Dark Times Roll
我们还以为你死了！
I thought you were dead!
瞪瞪瞪灯
Surprise!
姐好震惊啊 想想看
And colour me shocked ... imagine,
不结盟的淫妖终于从她双腿间
the unaligned Succubus finally yanking her head out from
昂起头颅
between her shapely legs and
加入了重要的一方
coming over to the only side that matters.
这可不是我选的
Well it wasn't by choice, lady.
一找到Vex我就要宣布这事无效
And I'm having it annulled, soon as you give me Vex.
Vex？那变态啥时候
Vex?Since when is that pervert capable
腰部以上有功能了
of anything above the belt.
他可是把你的下流小屁屁关起来了哟
He imprisoned your brassy beaver.
对 Vex是坏人 傻x幻术师Vex
Right: Vex bad. Vex mesmer poop.
亲 要是你要找Vex
Sweetie, if it's Vex you want,
下午来参加我的黑暗同乐会吧
come to my Dark Ceilidh this aft.
黑暗桶乐？肯德基新产品？
Dark kale-y? What is that code for vegetable enema.
黑暗同乐会跟光明宴会只有一个小区别
A Dark Ceilidh is like a Light Fae party except with more...
那就是啥都有
everything!
除了淫妖啥都有
Everything except a Succubus.
谢了 我自己去找Vex好了
Thanks, but I'll catch up to Vex on my own.
听着 你要是是被骗加入的黑暗
Look, if you were hoodwinked into joining the Dark,
给出证据你就可以脱身了
you can get out of it simply by showing proof.
真的？
Really?
坏消息是你这个证据
The bad news is you have to show proof
必须要在你加入后的第一个满月前出示
before the first full moon since you joined.
那不就是今晚
That's tonight.
哦 对哈
Oh, right.
那可没时间浪费了是吧
Well, there's no time to dawdle then, is there?
随便你想带你的宠物也行
Feel free to bring your human pet.
我不是宠物
I'm not a pet.
我不会当任何人的宠物 别的人类也不会
I will never be anyone's pet, nor will any human.
看吧 已经摸清黑暗派的准则了
See? Already getting the hang of being Dark.
真的啊~？
Really?
我是说 闭嘴
I mean, shut up.
随便穿什么都行
Show up in whatever makes you comfortable.
不过有个东西可不能丢
Though there is one thing you might consider wearing for once.
那是？
What's that?
微笑
A smile.
哦亲
Oh brother.
给我点消息
Just get me something,
任何关于流浪者的消息都行
anything on this Wanderer,
我们可以共进晚餐 Wai Lin
Wai Lin, and we'll do dinner.
*Wai Lin  2x13里让Dyson意识到他无法爱上Ciara的异种*
就晚饭
Just dinner.
不请自来 你好大的胆子
How dare you enter my private quarters without invitation.
酒保不需要那么大把刀吧
That is a big knife for a bartender.
那要看是什么酒吧了
Depends on the bar.
你被召唤了
You've been summoned
Una Mens有事和你谈
by the Una Mens for a personal inquisition
准备好你的故事吧
so get your story straight.
什么故事
Which story.
你这辈子的故事
Your life story.
哇
Wow!
你是说的黑暗异种 对吧
You said "Dark" Fae, right?
请为了我们的未来种棵树
"Please plant a tree in honour of our future"
环保主义者？姿势木讷？一个肌肉男都没见着？
Tree huggers? Bad swag? Not a UFC fighter in sight?
*UFC 中技格斗锦标赛  肌肉男互殴的比赛*
这可是我参加过的最挫的黑暗舞会了
This is the worst Dark Fae party we've ever been to.
我们就参加过这一个
This is the only Dark Fae party we've ever been to.
以后也不会参加了
And the only one we're ever going to.
那就让我放纵下吧亲
Well then I best embrace my bad-girl. 'Scuse me.
恩~ 黑暗一辈子
Mhm.Dark side for life!
耶~!
Yeah!
可别让小棍子戳到你眼睛
Okay well, Swizzlesticks do not let them poke out your eye.
*指鸡尾酒里固定水果，装饰用的小棍子*
啊 嘉宾在此
There she is, the guest of honour!
看看你 犀利到爆
Look at you, all edgy and shit.
真会吸引眼球啊
You sure know how to grab the spotlight.
尝过自助台了吗？
Have you tried the buffet?
人人都有份
There is something for everyone...
人类自助？
A human buffet?
我赌这个是香草口味而且回味无穷
I bet this one starts with vanilla and has a long, smoky finish.
赶紧走 把你的朋友也带上
Leave here at once. And take your friends with you.
让食物走掉了 真失礼呢
Dismissing the food? Kind of gauche, no
这就是为啥我不可能是黑暗派
That's why there's no way I'm Dark.
拜托 我们和光明根本是半斤八两
Please. We're no different from the Light.
我刚才鄙视你了吗 没错
Did I get judgey on you just now? Yes!
但我现在鄙视完了
But I'm already over it.
艾玛我真是荣幸
Oh! My day is saved.
因为我们不虚伪
Because there's a refreshing lack of hypocrisy with us.
我们老实承认自己是什么样的人 Bo
We're honest about what we are, Bo.
你为什么不这样
So why aren't you?
我知道我是谁
I know who I am.
你是只甜美的淫妖
You're a luscious Succubus
吸食人类是你的天性
who's true nature is to feed off humans
就和别的异种一样
like the rest of us Fae.
你只不过不乐意那样
You just choose not to.
傻了吧唧的
Lame; but whatevs.
不过你的头发挺好看
You've got great hair.
所以大家才盯着我看？
Is that why everyone's looking at me?
是的 他们都很高兴你找到自己的归属地了
Oh. They're delighted that you've found your true home.
他们为你高兴
They're happy for you.
黑暗派才不是我的归属 我来这也不是
The Dark Fae is not my home, and I'm not here
为了让你脸上有光
to make you look good in front of your subjects.
我只想问问Vex我怎么就要为你效力了
I just want to ask Vex how I ended up pledged to you goons.
他在哪
So where is he?
哦 某处吧
Oh. Somewhere.
我不知道 你得找他
I don't know. You're going to have to look for him.
你说他会来的
You said he'd be here.
我说你想找他 就得参加宴会
No, I said if you wanted him,you'd have to come to the party.
现在你来了 我可以提供各种帮助
And now that you're here, I'm gonna give you every resource
让你找到他
in order for you to hunt him down.
那我就恭敬不如从命 这就上路
Well, I'll just collect my gift bag and be on my way.
Una Mens在和老娘过不去
The Una Mens is cramping my style,
他们还想弄死你爱的所有人类
and they want every human that you love very, very dead.
我能保护我的朋友
I can protect my friends.
事情解决完之前他们是不会走的
Una Mens won't leave town until all loose ends are tied up.
Vex就是其中之一
And Vex is the loosest end of all.
为啥
Why is that?
因为他消失了 还惹恼了他们
'Cause he's vanished and somehow pissed them off.
我得找他
I need to find him.
显然你也要找他
And apparently you need to find him too.
不如就称作天意
I'd call that kismet.
不如就称作姐走了你傻x
Well, I'd call it kiss my ass while I walk away
我要按自己的意愿行事
and do this on my own terms.
你现在是黑暗派了Bo
You're Dark now, Bo.
就是说我不但是你女王 还是你朋友
That means I'm not only your boss, but I'm your friend.
我想跟你证明作为朋友我绝对够格
And I wanna prove to you how good a friend I can be.
我们要求跟Fitzpatrick McCorrigan谈话
We call to order the inquisition of Fitzpatrick McCorrigan.
*Fitzpatrick McCorrigan  Trick的全名*
你问什么 我就答什么
A question asked, an answer given.
结果会对你的未来大有影响
The result will carry great weight in determining your future.
你有随从吗?
Have you brought a second?
我向来独立行事
I take care of my own affairs.
好吧
So be it.
你怎么会到这个殖民地的
How did you come to be here in the colonies?
我要说在摩洛哥拐错了弯 你信吗
Would you believe I took a wrong turn at Morocco?
我们有好多话要讲
I guess we have a lot to talk about.
是啊 我们真该好好谈谈
Yeah, I guess we should.
哦天啊  这裙子真漂亮
Oh boy...this dress is incredible.
让我来把它脱掉吧
Let's get you out of it.
统计
Stat.
哦……医生用语……
Ooh, Doctor talk...![chuckles]
需要迷你蛋饼吗？
Uh ... Mini quiche?
*Quiche 一种馅饼类点心*
滚
Get. Out.
你……要不把吃的留下好了
Are you...maybe just leave the tray.
谦虚的异种开了酒吧 赢得一些赞誉
A humble Lakin Chan opens a bar and gains some prominence.
大家确实喜欢喝点烈酒
People do enjoy a stiff drink.
木豆酒吧被叫成庇护所
The Dal Riata was declared a place of sanctuary.
让你光明黑暗通吃
It gained you influence with the Light and the Dark.
我不参与异种的政治
I keep my nose out of Fae politics.
你应该听说过Una Mens是怎么来的
You must know how the Una Mens came to be.
异种大战后 暴动出现了
After the Great Fae War,there was a rebellion.
反叛的异种试图推翻血王的血之法律
Fae rebels trying to overturn the blood laws of the Blood King.
那是为什么
Why was that?
他被腐蚀了
He became corrupt.
和平唾手可得 只要他放权给
But a peace was offered, if The King would relinquish power
一个议会 其中成员自愿牺牲 他们的个人渴求和不足
to a council made up of those willing to sacrifice their individual flaws and desires.
还有灵魂
And souls.
那是为了构成一个没有自我没有野心的单一灵魂
To form a single soul without ego or ambition.
血王同意了
The Blood King agreed.
然后他背叛了我们
Then he betrayed us.
六个神圣的纸莎草种子 由六个异种吞下
The six seeds of the sacred papyrus plant were given to six Fae to swallow.
他们因此而获得新生 成为谦逊和公正的容器
So they might be blessed with new life as a single vessel of humility and justice.
国王把种子偷走 消失了
The King stole his seed and vanished.
吸收了血圣的能力 Una Mens就可以
Absorb the power of the blood mage and the Una Mens
保证他书写的法律不被破坏
will be able to enforce the laws he wrote, unchallenged.
不被破坏？
Unchallenged?
我们会承认他的地位
We would have him take his rightful place among us.
假如我们能找到他
If we might find him.
你说了有跳舞的
You said there'd be dancing.
不然为啥我们大吃特吃啊亲
Why do you think we're carbo loading, Footloose?
他们看起来不挺好的
These people don't seem so bad.
黑暗和光明到底有啥区别
What's the difference between Light and Dark anyway?
光明派都是些混蛋
Well, the Light are assholes.
黑暗派是……
And The Dark ...
乐趣多多多的混蛋
are assholes who have fun.
寿司！
Sushi!
恩恩恩恩辣味三文鱼卷？
Mmmm, spicy salmon roll
嗨Kenzi
Hi, Kenzi.
Bruce?
*南太平洋小岛  风景如画*
Bruce我还以为你在波拉波拉岛
Bruce I thought you were in Bora Bora!
我真不想你看到我这样子
I really didn't want you to see me like this.
天啊 你是男体盛吗？
My god! Are you a living sushi table?
你是布寿司
You're... Brushi!
哦哦哦 密制酱料
Oooh, special sauce...!
嘿 你可不能吃长龙卷
Hey! No dragon roll for you!
*鳗鱼黄瓜和牛油果做的寿司 通常摆成一个长卷上桌 此处刚好放在Bruce的丁丁处*
Bruce起来
Bruce get up.
这是我的惩罚
But this is my punishment...
起来 Bruce
Get up, Bruce.
哦天啊 好吧
Oh, good lord. Okay.
得把这个块姜拿下来
Okay. We're gonna get this ginger off you,
给你找件衬衫和尊严
find you a shirt and some dignity to go with it.
王薇薇
Vera Wang!
*著名婚纱品牌*
哦不
Oh no.
发生了啥事
What. Is. Happening?!
你不会以为黑暗派会真的出钱搞这些吧？
You didn't think the Dark legitimately pays for stuff like this, did you?!
寿司坏掉了!
Bad sushi everyone!
他们用抑扬格五音步读婚誓 好可爱
They read their vows in iambic pentameter. So lovely.
*抑扬格五音步 一种英文诗歌常见的格律*
走吧大家
Move it, people!
我们真是有好多话要说
We really do have a lot to talk about...
我们真的应该谈谈
We should do that sometime...
我想去找你来着……
I wanted to find you...
我得走了
I had to go...
Bo我很高兴你来了
Bo, I'm just so glad that you're here.
你为什么会在这
Why are you here?
Vex跟流浪者不知道怎么的把我变黑暗了
Vex somehow worked with the Wanderer to turn me Dark.
你是黑暗派了？
You're Dark???
我就是……过来找Vex想变回去
I just...I came here to find Vex to reverse it.
我就没想到……
And I just never imagined...
天啊我担心死你了
God, I've been worried sick about you.
结果你没事人一样跟m女王在这
And here you are, chilling with the Morrigan...
不是没事 我是在躲Una Mens
Not chilling so much as hiding in terror from the Una Mens.
多谢m女王了
Thanks to the Morrigan.
当然
Of course,
我想知道到底特么发生了什么事
I wanna hear what the hell happened...
我想告诉你
And I wanna tell you.
但现在好像你得走了
But right now it sounds like you need to get going.
哦 马上
Oh, in a second.
无聊！
Booorrr-ing!
接下来你俩要互相梳头了吗？
What's next, are you going to braid each other's hair?
怎么还没开始磨豆腐
Scissor already!
我们要是想要有观众 早就卖门票了好吗
If we'd wanted an audience,we would've charged admission.
就这速度 老娘早敲碗要退票了
And at this rate, I would have asked for a refund.
好吧 说正经的
Fine. Back to business, I suppose.
你们谈吧
I'll leave you two...
不我想你参与
No, I want you to hear this.
Bo 我会帮你找Vex
Bo I will give you the means to run down Vex
只要你以血起誓你会把他交给我
if you give me your blood oath to bring him to me.
先听听这代表着什么
Lets hear what the means is, first.
我好高兴和你们一起合作！
I'm so freaking excited to be working with you!
要不把之前那个服务生也叫来算了
Why don't we just invite the waiter back in?
不 不 这事不能太多人知道
No. No.Only those who need to know.
我想那就是说我很……
I guess that makes me...?
相当重要
Essential.
Bo需要一个让Vex失去能力的药
Bo's gonna need a drug to make Vex powerless and compliant.
需要某个特殊的医生……画龙点睛
It's gonna need a certain Doctor's, mmm, touch.
那到底怎么搞
So what's the plan?
我们要出任务了！
We're going on a mission!
m女王的天使
Evony's Angels!
*恶搞查理的天使*
我给你们点时间准备一下
I'll give you a few moments to...collect yourselves.
来吧清道夫
Come along, scavenger.
几分钟不算长啊
A few minutes isn't a lot of time.
不浪费时间的话足够了
Waste not, want not.
今天是个好日子 心想的事儿都能成
This is the most amazing day...it's like a dream come true!
真的出任务
Being on an actual assignment with Bo,
和辣到不行的淫妖Bo 还有天才医生Lauren
the insanely hot Succubus,and Lauren the genius Doctor!
我居然不用无聊的数手指头玩 而是真的要出任务
I get to be part of something instead of having to devour sloppy seconds!
呕
Ew.
她是个清道夫异种
She's a scavenger Fae.
我觉得有点尿裤子了
I just peed myself a little.
哇
Wow.
Pietra很高兴你能加入
Great to have on board, Pietra,
不过现在是什么情况
but what are we doing here?
等下
Wait.
哦对
Oh! Right!
我听说的Vex的事都巨扯
I've heard the most totally shocking things about Vex.
被Una Mens和m女王追杀
With the Una Mens and the Morrigan after him,
财产被冻结 他只好东躲西藏
and all his assets frozen, he's been sticking to the shadows,
十面埋伏 身无分文
hunted, haunted, broken.
知道他怎么赚钱吗
Guess what he's been doing for cash
他在卖身
He's hookering!
你要帮忙不？
Do you need help?
没事 好好的
Nope, all good.
请好吧您
Just stay right there.
他就想跑出城
He's been dying to flee town.
但Una Mens的毒让他走不了
But the Una Mens poison is binding him to the territory.
这就是为啥他需要这个
That's why he needs this!
克洛诺斯的弯刀
The Scimitar of Cronus.
*克洛诺斯 希腊神话中宙斯之父*
这是切除毒药的唯一办法
It's the only way to cut out the poison!
他还以为我给他这个是为了
He thinks I'm stealing it form in exchange for taking me
他走之后能享用他的残羹冷炙
when he runs and giving me all his "leftover feeds."
但这只是卧底行动
But ...it's a total sting operation.
你要在哪把这个刀给他？
Where are you giving this blade to Vex?
还不知道 但是他准备好了会告诉我
I don't know yet. But he'll call when he's ready.
我可等不到他喝多了打电话
Well, I can't wait for him to drunk dial.
我得在月出前找到他
I need Vex before moonrise.
艾玛我让你失望了 极其十分非常的失望
Oh god, I'm failing you.I totally failing you.
没 Pietra你做得很好
No, Pietra, you're doing great.
你上次见到Vex是在哪
Where was the last place you saw Vex?
东面的旧铁路桥下面
Under the old railway bridge in the East end.
不就是Dyson搬去的那个健身馆那吗
Well that's by the gym that Dyson moved into.
Vex藏在他敌人家附近？
Vex is hiding near his arch enemy?
没人会怀疑那吧
No one would suspect it.
我们可以让狼把他闻出来
But we could get Dyson to sniff him out.
事实上 Dyson不在
Actually, Dyson is away...
他去找你了
looking for you.
哦
Oh.
好吧 Dyson不在
Well if Dyson's absent,
对Vex更好
that's even better for Vex.
他现在可以感觉完全安全了
He'll feel completely safe right now.
但是他还是会藏起来
But he would still be hiding.
那个地方任何黑暗异种在街上游荡
And in that area,any Dark Fae on the street...
都会引起极大的注意
would attract a lot of attention.
妥妥的 任何黑暗异种都会引起注意
That's right, any Dark Fae would attract attention.
你准备好活动筋骨了吗 Pietra
Are you ready for some real action, Pietra?
那当然
Yeah!
来吧
Let's do this!
好吧 作为帮助我的惩罚
Okay. So as punishment for helping me,
你被当成私有物品送给另外一个异种了
you were given to another Fae as property?
我成了舞娘Kai的奴隶
I'm the slave of Kai the Makishi.
*Makishi：赞比亚的洛瓦洛族的一种特殊舞蹈，舞者跳舞时会头戴面具*
她很刻薄
Kai is really mean.
可你给我寄了好多明信片
But you sent me all those postcards.
你白天潜水采蛤 晚上打呼啦高尔夫
You were clam diving all day and hula hoop golfing at night.
根本就没呼啦高尔夫这种东西，是吧
Hula hoop golf isn't a thing, is it.
我不想让你担心我
I didn't want you to worry about me.
可我现在很担心你 Bruce
Well now I'm worried, Bruce!
不过我们可以帮你 对吧
Well we can help you. Right?
对呀 对呀 我们可以帮你
Yes! Yes, we can help you!
我们该怎么帮你呢
How do we help you?
再找一个异种奴役我
Get another Fae to master me I guess.
奴役你
Master you?
事实比这听起来的更糟糕
It's much worse than it sounds.
任何异种都行?
Any Fae?
对
Yeah.
会有破事发生在奴役你的人身上吗
And does anything bad happen to someone who Masters you?
他们会完全对我负责
They become completely responsible for me until
直到我的惩罚结束
my punishment is fulfilled.
我占空间很多的
I take up a lot of space.
住废弃工厂空间不是问题
Space is cheap when you're squatting.
来 金毛酱
Alright, blondie ...
噢太好了
Oh yeah.
水下海绵园艺
Underwater sponge gardening?
根本没那种东西
Not a thing.
我就知道
I knew it.
大家好哇 我素Tamsin
Hi everybody, I'm Tamsin, wooo!
好 我要完全奴役 那边那个大块头Bruce
Anyway, I'm just gonna master all over that big guy Bruce over there!
所以Kai 不管你在哪儿
So Kai, wherever you are,
我要向你这个喝三鹿长大的家伙挑战
up yours you big dong-head!
噢 这才叫爬踢嘛
Oh! Now it's a party ...
有人放话挑战
a challenge has been made.
这包袱的现任主人
The current holder of the burden has
拥有捍卫他们财产的权利
the right to defend their property.
决斗者们 向前一步
Duelists, step forward!
决斗者？
Duelists?
绝对是真的
Totally a thing
噢 我小肥羊个海底捞呀
Oh, Swizzlesticks.
针里是什么
What's in the needle?
紫罗兰的花蜜
Nectar of violet
非常罕见
It's extremely rare,
不过黑暗异种的温室里有一大把
but turns out the Dark Fae have oodles of it in their greenhouse.
你能想像吗?
Can you imagine?
苏格拉底用的最原汁原味的迷幻药
Socrates' original hallucinogenic?
好厉害哦
Hmm. Mind. Blown.
那我们的谈话呢
So how about that talk?
谈话?
Talk?
谈话!
Talk!
现在?
Now?
现在 我们得在这呆上一段时间
Now! We could be here a while.
你想从哪里开始
Where do you want to start
不知道 我们分手的事？
I dunno. Our break.
Taft那发生的事
What happened at Taft's.
Karen
Karen...
对 这个Karen是谁
Yeah, who is this Karen person?
我们怎么落入了黑暗派的手掌之中
How we came into the clutches of the Dark Fae...
回到这个Karen
Back to this Karen.
侬好
Hello
等等 等等
Wait wait wait...
我勒个去
Oh, shit!
就知道Vex那么聪明 绝对不会自己现身的
Of Course. Vex is too smart to show himself.
哇 很明显他在控制那个女人
Whoa. He's clearly controlling that woman.
他肯定在哪儿藏着
He has to be here somewhere...
我不喜欢这个
I don't like this...
奥
Ow!!
人家被推倒了 被推倒了
Woman down! Woman down!
Pietra
Pietra!
我在激烈斗争中光荣负伤了 太牛了
I totally got wounded in action.This is so awesome.
我的娘 好痛
Oh god, it hurts!
你要是不闭嘴我让你更痛
I'll hurt you if you don't be quiet.
Bo 我来搞定
Bo, I go this.
只是淤青而已
Okay, it's just bruised.
告诉我真相吧医生 我是不是要失去一条腿了
Tell me the truth, Doc,am I gonna lose the leg?
不会 但是你再不安静 你可能会失去一条舌头
No, but you might lose a tongue if you don't be quiet.
我找到他就叫你
I'll call when I find him!
Bo 你需要这个
Bo! You're gonna need this.
我就那么一说哈 我觉得你俩在一起很不错
For the record? I think you make a great couple.
Bo 我风骚的小讨厌精
Bo, my sultry little suckface!
你什么时候开始帮Morrigan做脏活了
Since when did you start doing the Morrigan's dirty work
自从你和流浪者把我骗成黑暗派开始
Since you and the Wanderer tricked me into becoming Dark Fae.
现在你要撤消你对我做的事情
And now you're gonna undo it.
流浪者
The Wanderer
噢 那是我妈妈为了不让我出去骗人
Oh. That's a tall tale me mum told to scare me
给我讲的恐怖故事
from fiddling with myself in public.
不过我还没时间听关于狼外婆的故事
But I haven't got time for stories about bogeyman.
*bogeyman：西方文化里家长用来教育和恐吓孩子的经典角色*
哥得上路了
I'm hitting the road,
所以撒哟拉拉 再也不见
so it's sayonara and see you never.
很抱歉搞砸了你的离别会
Sorry to crash your going away party.
不过我已经下了血誓
But I've given my blood oath
要把你那皮包骨的屁股带回Morrigan面前
to haul your bony ass to the Morrigan.
喂 这是钢管舞者的美臀 在这儿呢
Hey. This is a pole-dancer's ass, this is.
所以去死吧
So piss off.
先为你头上要出现的大头包道歉
Sorry in advance about the goose-egg!
啊 香蕉他个芭勒啊
Ahhh...Swizzlesticks.
噢 哇
Oh, whoa.
天 那注射器里是什么东西
God, what was in that syringe?
哦对 苏格拉底
Oh yeah... Socrates.
所有东西都是 粉红色的
Everything's all... pink.
我为什么在这里 Dyson
Why am I here...? Dyson
哦不好意思 亲爱的
Oh, no. Sorry, luv,
Dyson出去咬自己尾巴玩了
Dyson's out chasing his own tail.
这就是说 你和我 简直可以一起玩
Which means you and I can, like, totally hang out.
放我走
Let me go...
可以啊 请便
Oh yeah, by all means.
哦 怎么了 你动不了
Oh, what's that, you can't move?
是不是有人被前任的小尖尖东西给制缚了
Well didn't someone get box-blocked by her ex's pointy thing.
看看 哥又搞笑了
Oh, look at that, I made a funny!
不 你犯了一个错误
No, you made a mistake...
不管了 你就是我的筹码
Anyway, you're my leverage.
以防我在逃脱过程中碰钉子
In case I hit any snags in getting out of Dodge.
不 不 不 你不能走
No, no, no. You can't leave...
不 我恐怕 我可以而且必须走
No, I can and must, I'm afraid.
在我做完一个重要的手术后
After I perform some necessary surgery.
噢 真锋利呀
Ohhh, sharp indeed.
用来割淫妖那柔软可爱的喉咙最适合不过了
Perfect for slittings Succubus' soft and lovely throat.
艾马 艾马  连星星火花都没有
My, my. Not even a spark.
医生搞的鸡尾酒真厉害啊
Quite the cocktail that Doctor cooked up.
Lauren
Lauren...
我们又在一起了
and we're back together...
她给了我一条漂亮的项链
She got me a really pretty necklace.
那真的只是暂时的分手
It really was just a break.
如果你再不停地在那琼瑶
If you don't stop gushing,
我保证我特马要自刎了
I swear I'll slit my own bloody throat.
等等 对 我气你让我加入了黑暗派
Wait, yeah! I'm pissed at you for making me join the Dark.
他们很恶心 而且他们带走了Lauren
They're gross and they took Lauren
而且月亮就快升起来了
the moon will be up soon.
你真的需要告诉我你和你的烟不停口先生怎么设的局
You really need to tell me how you and Sir Smokes-a-lot tricked
这样我才能退出结盟
me so I can un-join them...
我 爷 老子
Me! Me! Me!!
太阳不是围着你转的 知道吗
It's not all about you, you know.
我发誓我想赶快离开这个城市 想得不能再想了
I swear I can't get out of this town fast enough.
啊
Agh!
好 你是Valkyrie 你只需要在她身上施加疑惑
Okay. You're a Valkyrie. All you need to cast doubt on her,
然后往她肚子上来上一膝盖
and then knee her in the ovaries.
诶~听起来不太好耶
That doesn't sound very nice.
你是黑暗派的
Look you're dark Fae.
她也是黑暗派的 做任何事情都是可以的
She's dark Fae. Everything is allowed.
这场决斗将会是血淋淋的激烈互殴
This fight's gonna be a bloody slug fest.
我是说 你会没事的 别担心
I mean, you're gonna be totally fine, don't worry.
保护好你的脸就好
Just protect your face, ok?
女士们 先生们 还有马屁精们
Ladies, lords, and lickspittles!
下面开始主人之间的对决  直到死亡
It's time to commence the master duel... to the death!
反面 挑战者选择战斗的方式
Tails! Challenger chooses the mode of combat.
会是什么呢 甜心。。。手枪 剑术
What'll it be, honey? Pistols? Swords?
伦家就是想跳舞
I just wanna dance!
好 什么事情都有第一次
Okay, first time for everything,
那么就是舞林争霸  直到死亡
dance-off it is... to the death!
哦这味道可真恶心
Oh that smells disgusting.
跟你说哦 这是重要的麻醉剂
Mind you, it's a necessary anesthetic
为了我的自我截肢准备的
for the self-amputation I'll be performing.
自我截啥 怎么做?
Self ampu-what-now?
哦 整只手都得被砍掉
Oh yeak. The whole hand has to come off.
Una Mens 特马的法西斯 算了 至少我不会有任何感觉
Una Mens, bloody fascists. Well, at least I won't feel a thing.
Vex 别做那么极端的事
Vex ... don't do anything drastic...
哦不 不用担心
-Oh no, don't worry about it.
这服牛逼的药是我一个牛逼的爱人教我的
This is a potent potion taught to me by a potent love,
很久很久以前
once upon a time.
你想谈爱情吗?
You wanna talk love?
看看Lauren 我是说 她就没有做全截肢
Look at Lauren ... I mean, she didn't do a full amputation,
她只是休了个小息
she just took a little break
你特么能不提她么？！
Do you ever shut up about her?!
现在休息结束了 我们又在一起了 一点隔阂都没有
And now the break is over, and we're back together with barely a bruise.
看到了吧 没有狗血 也没有永久伤害
See? Nothing drastic, nothing permanent.
只有 恩
Just... hmmm.
那是什么声音?
What's that sound?
我心里唱的歌儿 你想再听一下吗?
That is the song of my heart.You wanna hear it again?
哦当然 我太乐意了
Oh, yeah. I'd love to.
哦 煮沸了
Oh, boiling.
喂  Vex
Hey, Vex!
我从来不知道你是这样的大混蛋 我没错吧
I never knew you are such an asshole. Am I right
对 对 你说的都对
Yes, yes, all valid points...
我一点都不明白 你知道的 我是最后一个催眠师
I don't undertake this lightly. You know, I'm the last mesmer.
人们惧怕我的种族的力量
My kind were feared for their powers,
过去几千年 所有的异种都在围剿和屠杀我们
hunted down and slaughtered through the ages by all the Fae
他们屠杀的办法
and the manner in which they did it, well...
你想知道是什么吗
You wanna know how?
他们的双手都被砍断
Their hands were cut off.
催眠师除了残肢什么都没有 不能进食
Mesmers with nothing but stumps, unable to feed.
他们在缓慢 痛苦 羞辱的情况下死去
They died a slow, painful and humiliating death.
我看见这事发生在我的整个家族身上
I saw it happen to my entire family,
我的兄弟 我的父亲 还有我的母亲
my brother, my father...and my mother.
我对我自己发誓 我绝对不会让同样的事情在我身上发生
I promised myself I would never let that happen to me.
所以我尽可能的生存下去
So I did what I had to do to survive
变成了我今天的样子
and become what I am today.
黑暗的奴仆
A servant of the Dark.
我会想念Ginger
I will miss Ginger.
*和下文中的Fred是Vex给自己的手起的名字*
不过至少我还能和Fred一起跳舞
But at least I'll still be able to dance with Fred.
Tamsin 还记得那个舞吗？5， 6， 7， 8
Tamsin! Remember the dance? 5, 6, 7, 8...
耶  耶
Yeah!Yeah!
哇  哇
Whoa! Whoa!
现在是时候用你的疑惑之术了
Now would be the time to use your power of doubt on her.
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can.
气沉丹田
Just breathe from the diaphragm
收腹提臀 去吧
and clench your butt cheeks. Do it!
我觉得我提得太厉害了
I think I clenched my cheeks too hard.
瓦尔基里获得了这个渣渣异种的奴役权
The Valkryie has mastered the disgraced Fae!
干得不错 我们含苞待放的战士小公主
Well done, our blooming warrior-princess!
醒醒 亲爱的
Chin-chin, luv.
滚滚长江东逝水
Come get your duds in order
*歌曲为Heave away - the Fables*
浪花淘尽英雄 是非成败转头空青山
cause we're bound across the water
青山依旧在 几度夕阳红
Heave away, me jollies, heave away...
白发渔樵江渚上 惯看秋月春风
Come get your duds in order
一壶浊酒喜相逢
'cause we're bound to leave tomorrow
古今多少事 都付笑谈中
heave my boys, we're all bound away...
Vex Vex!
Vex! Vex!
我知道你现在很孤独
I know how alone you are right now.
那么多藏身之所
Out of all the places you could have come to hide
你偏偏跑来Dyson这里 因为在你那
you came to Dyson's. Because somewhere deep in that
卑鄙 黑暗内心的深处 你 你想让我们找到你
despicable, black heart of yours, you... wanted us to find you!
才没有!
Did not!
我 Kenzi 甚至Dyson
Me, and Kenzi, and even Dyson...
我们是你唯一的家人了
we're the only family you have left.
啊 混合物开始在这个魔法霉菌上起反作用了
ah the concoction is having an adverse affect on this magic mold.
这本来应该只是麻醉药的
It was supposed to be an anesthetic...!
妈妈爸爸呀 好烫！
Mother-father, it burns!
古今多少事 都付笑谈中
Heave away, me jollies, we're all 'bout away ... !
Vex!
哦
Oh...
哦 糟糕 我应该拿右座主驾驶的车的
Oh, bollocks. I should have got the right hand drive.
Vex
Vex!
求你了 别把我带回Morrigan那
Please. Don't take me back to the Morrigan.
你真只在乎你自己 不是吗?
You really only care about yourself, don't you?
怎么 这样不好吗?
What. And that's bad...?
我干嘛要帮你 哪怕是一点点
Why should I help you one bit
你都不告诉我怎么停止我在黑暗派的誓约
when you won't even tell me how I ended up pledged to the Dark?
因为我知道个屁啊
Because I know jack-shit about it!
我以为你在讲笑呢
I thought you were having a laugh.
我以为是注射器的作用
I thought it was the effect of the syringe.
事实上 我以为你是脑残
Actually I thought you were soft in the head.
啊 不 不 不
Ahm...No, no, and no.
我真的向黑暗派立约结盟 我也真的不知道是怎么发生的
I really am pledged to the Dark,I really don't know how it happened.
我真的需要在月亮升起来之前知道答案
And I really need answers before moonrise.
那你为什么不去问M姐姐的档案员
So, why didn't you just ask the Morrigan's Archivist?
档案员
Archivist?
对 那家伙的手指尖存有所有的细节
Yeah, bloke will have all the details at his fingertips.
你确定你脑子没进水
Are you sure you're not soft in the head?
当然 她当然耍我了
Of course. Of course she played me.
那么 我们之间没事了吧?
So, uh everything's good between us, yeah?
你会放我走吧?
You're gonna let me go?
因为毕竟 如果你把我带回给Morrigan
Because after all, if you take me back to the Morrigan,
她会把我折磨到死 我会很自责看到
she'll torture me to death,and I would hate to see that
你纯洁百合般的良心守到谴责
stain your lily white conscience.
行 投我以桃 报之以李 好吗?
Well, I'll take the clutch,and you take the stick, yeah?
好 让我们早点把这事结束了
All right, let's get this over with.
月亮几分钟以后就要升起来了
The moon will rise in minutes.
我知道你能告诉我到底发生了什么
And I know you can tell me what happened.
Vex呢?
Where's Vex?
哦 你说我那个从来就不想要的 烦人的又讨厌
Oh. You mean the annoying brother I kinda hate,never wanted,
以及变成一半的催眠师的兄弟吗?
and is half the mesmer he used to be?
顺便一提 谢谢你把我耍的团团转
Thanks for sending me on a wild goose chase, by the way.
我需要整个Vex来摆脱Una Mens
I need all of Vex to get rid of the Una Mens.
你把他带来  是在为当地异种们做了大好事
You're doing a real solid for all the local Fae by bringing him in.
我不会把他带来给你折磨和杀害的
I won't let you torture and kill him.
哦 亲亲 甜心 我的达令 不像光明派
Oh. Honey, honey, honey ...unlike the Light Fae,
我们不会累计怨恨的啦
we don't hold grudges.
我唯一关心的是摆脱Una Mens
All I care about is getting rid of the Una Mens.
不过如果你很关心Vex
But if you feel that strongly 'bout Vex,
你可以宣称Vex是你的责任
you can claim Vex as your responsibility.
然后就是你的责任管好他了
And then it'll be on your head to keep him in line.
你想忍受这个还是闭嘴
You ready to put up or shut up?
好吧  档案员 现在
Fine. Archivist. Now.
哦 你知道了 我都猜不到
Ooo, you figured it out, I never would have guessed.
档案员 她终于像点黑暗派出来的了
Archivist! She's finally getting her Dark shit together!
任何对黑暗派许下的誓约都会出现在这里
Any pledge to the Dark shows up here.
谢谢
Thanks...?
这里是你的签名 然后这里是你的保证人
There's your signature.And there's your sponsor's.
哦 Rainer是谁
Oh... Who's Rainer?
布吉岛唷
Not a clue.
把这撕了 我是被整了
Tear this up. I was obviously tricked.
我根本不记得签了这货
I have no memory of signing it.
月亮还没升起 我们还有时间
The moon isn't up yet, we still have time.
哦 亲 我很抱歉 我最近总是试着在跟我朋友撒谎的时候
Oh dear, I'm sorry ... I really am trying to be more poetic
显得更琼瑶一点
these days when I lie to my friends.
这让生活更有趣
It makes life so much more interesting.
我要.....
I'm going to ...
你什么都不要做
You're going to nothing.
你现在是黑暗派的人了 你得对我付出忠诚
You are a subject of the Dark now,and you owe me your loyalty.
这个宣言是神圣 必须遵守的契约
This declaration is a sacred,binding agreement,
就连我都没有能力改变它
and not even I have the power to overturn it.
只有你的神秘保证人能够帮你
Only your mystery sponsor can help you with that.
祝你运气好能找到他 不管他是谁
And good luck finding him. Whoever he is.
那是我的
That's mine.
你来拿呀
Come and get it.
算了 你留着吧
You know what, keep it.
我现在有新玩具玩了
I have new toys to entertain me.
你还有什么要说的吗
Is there anything you wish to add
我只是希望你能保留点你曾经的灵魂 Arabella
Only that I hope you've retained some of the soul you once had，Arabella
知道我们在许下庄严的誓约前
To know us by the names we had before
拥有过的名字是一种亵渎
we took our solemn vows is unholy!
我知道你为了点小罪就把你整个家族都交出去了
I know that you turned in your own family for petty crimes
当你变成六人之一后
when you became one of the six.
真是亵渎神明的言词
This is blasphemy.
你怎么能让血圣做同样的事
How could you ask The Blood King to do the same
为了他创造的法律 他把唯一的女儿交出来了
He'd turned in his own daughter in order to satisfy the rules that he'd created.
而他创造的法律是残酷的
And what he created was cruelty.
你把正统错误的理解为残酷了
You mistake orthodoxy for cruelty.
但是 我们不能期待我们的候选人是完美的
Still, we cannot expect our candidates to be perfect.
你的历史 信仰
With your history, your standing,
知识 你是唯一的选择
and your knowledge, you are the only choice.
选择
Choice?
作为临时Ash
For acting Ash.
我讨厌那女人 满嘴跑火车
I hate that woman. Full moon bullshit.
结果我不能让自己退出黑暗
Turns out I can't un-dark myself.
一定会有办法的
There has to be a way.
噢 至少现在你回来了
Ohh. At least I have you back.
来吧 让我带你回家 接风洗尘
Come on. Let me take you home and we'll wash away
去除这一身的假装和操纵，比如说
this double-dealing and manipulation in, say,
洗一个大大的鸳鸯泡泡浴
a giant claw-foot bathtub?
再说 冰块快要融化了
Besides... this ice is gonna melt.
嗨 怎么了?
Hey, what's wrong?
我想我没办法回去那里了 光明派那儿
I don't think that I can go back there.With the Light.
我不懂
I don't understand.
当Una Mens开始残杀人类时 我逃了
When the Una Mens started killing humans, and I ran,
光明派压根就没想过要来找我
the Light never bothered to come looking for me.
黑暗派呢 他们找到了我 保护我
But the Dark? They sought me out, offered me protection.
Lauren
Lauren...
当然了 他们搞得很狗血
Sure, they were drama queens about it,
让我给他们的老人诊断 考验我
tested me by forcing me to diagnose one of elders.
但是他们来了 当没有任何人来的时候
But they came ... when no one else did.
我会来救你的 但是
I would have come, but...
但是你不能 我知道 Bo
... but you couldn't. I know. I'm not angry Bo.
我不生你的气
With you.
给黑暗派工作 我可以随时想来就来 想走就走
With the Dark, I can come and go as I please.
我自愿和他们一起 没有束缚的契约
I'm with them on my terms. No binding agreements.
也没有狗链子 我真不敢相信我说了这些
There's no dog collar. I can't believe I'm saying this,
但是Bo 我头一次觉得自由
but for the first time Bo, I feel free.
但是我可以让你自由 我们可以一起自由飞
But I could free you. We can be free together!
怎么做?
How?
为你而战 保护你 认领你 如果我必须这样的话
Fight for you. Protect you.Claim you, if I have to...
你的意思是做我的主人?
You mean own me?
你是异种  我是人类
You're Fae, I'm human.
那又怎么样?
So what?
那样 我永远都是阶下囚
So, I'll always be a prisoner.
至少 我能选择自己的牢笼
The least I can do is choose my own cage.
没事的 Bo
It's gonna be okay Bo.
现在你是黑暗派了 我可以随时看到你
Now that you're Dark ...I'll see you around.
当你准备好回到你真正的家人身旁时
When you're ready to come back to your real family,
说一声就好
just say the word.
现在你自由了 Bruce
Not that you're free, Bruce.
为什么你不真的就去波拉波拉岛 或者随便哪里
Why don't you actually go to Bora Bora. Or wherever.
就出发寻找自我
Just take off and find yourself.
我不知道 我总是Morrigan的手下
I don't know.I've always been the Morrigan's man.
杀手 保镖
A killer, a protector.
我不会做其他的事情
I can't really do anything else.
也许你不能 但你不试试怎么会知道呢 大个子
Maybe not, but you'll never know until you give it a shot, big guy.
找到你的翅膀 布寿司 飞吧
Find your wings, Brushi. Fly.
你造吗?
You know
带回家一只流浪狗 好吧 一直受伤的小鸟 不错
Bring home a stray puppy, okay. A wounded bird, fine.
但我从来没想过有天我的外孙女
But I never thought I'd see the day when my granddaughter
会在我门口带着一只手的催眠师出现
would show up at my doorstep with a one-handed mesmer
还声明她加入了黑暗派
claiming she threw in with the Dark.
这事儿科学吗
Is this thing legit?
我相信是的
I believe it is.
你加入了黑暗派
You joined the Dark.
但是你会帮我想办法处理这堆烂摊子
But you'll help me figure out how to fix this mess?
但愿如此 Bo 但是事情太复杂了
I hope so, Bo. But things have gotten complicated.
怎么复杂
How?
Una Mens想给光明派找保姆
The Una Mens need a caretaker for the Light Fae.
然后他们决定任命我为临时Ash
And they've decided to name me... the acting Ash.
那我的外公是光明派的头头咯
So my grandfather is the head of the Light?
而我的外孙女是黑暗派的甜心
And my granddaughter is the darling of the Dark.
Una Mens肯定爱死这出戏了
The Una Mens must be loving this.
他们不会爱也不会恨  没有感情
They don't love. They don't hate. No emotions.
那他们还剩什么?
What else is there?
法律 如果你不照他们想的去做
Rules. And if you don't follow them willingly...
他们会想尽一切让你做
they'll do whatever it takes to make you.
过程不会是愉悦的
And it won't be pleasant.
我们家真是一团糟啊
Our family is such a mess.
但是 Isabeau 我们对付过去了
Yet somehow, Isabeau, we muddle through.
那我这个所谓的保证人呢?
What about my so-called sponsor?
Rainer
Rainer.
只有一个办法可以找到他
There's only one sure way to find out who he is.
国王的记录之书
The Kings' Book of Records.
我们会找到的
We'll find it.
您要求的 淫妖的宣言
The Succubus' declaration, as you commanded.
Rainer
Rainer.
Rainer. Rainer.
不 不可能 绝对再不可能!
No, it can not be.Never again!